GALEN KELLNER

Midlothian, VA 23114

Phone: (804) 300-6242 | Email: kellnergp@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/galen-kellner-63b49b134/ | GitHub: github.com/kellnergp

SUMMARY

Biomedical Engineer and Data Analyst with an interest in data-driven solutions to engineering design problems. Experienced at working independently and coordinating with teammates to complete tasks within tight timeframes. Excels at learning new skills and solving complex problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools: Python, VBA, MATLAB, HTML/Javascript

Databases: PostgreSQL, Mondo

PROJECTS

Meteorites Dashboard | github.com/kellnergp/Meteorites-Fireballs-Interactive-Dashboard

- A Flask-managed interactive dashboard designed to present NASA data on Meteorites and Fireballs. It uses the Plotly and Leaflet Javascript libraries to generate interactive data views.
- Personally designed and implemented Leaflet maps of historical Meteorite and Fireball locations and data.
- HTML, Javascript, Python, Flask, Leaflet

Basketball Pro Prediction | github.com/kellnergp/BB_Pro_Prediction

- Uses web-scraped NCAA Basketball historical player stats to train a Random Forest Classifier model which predicts if a player is likely to play professionally after college.
- Personally responsible for coding and running web-scraping script, cleaning and collating gathered data, and adapting final model to accept user input for future players.
- Python, BeautifulSoup, Scikit-Learn

Mars News Scraping | github.com/kellnergp/mars-web-scraping

- Uses BeautifulSoup and Flask to scrape data and images from a series of Mars News and info sites and present the gathered information on a custom dashboard. Data is also stored in a Mongo database.
- Solo-developed based on a prompt.
- Python, BeautifulSoup, Flask, PyMongo, HTML

EXPERIENCE

Night Clerk 2019 – 2021

Kroger Midlothian, VA

Inventoried, restocked, and maintained the Meat and Seafood department. Involved working alone for extended periods and required proactive time management.

Assistant Manager/Cook

2017 - 2019

Vocelli Pizza Midlothian, VA

Prepared food, cleaned, handled money, served customers over the phone/in person, routed deliveries, and managed coworkers. Experienced customer service and team coordination in high-pressure and time-sensitive situations very regularly.

Undergraduate Research Assistant VCU Rehabilitative Technology Lab

2015 – 2016 Richmond, VA

Researched and worked on methods to convert images into planar views for the production of textured images using MATLAB code. Focused on developing code to solve technical problems independently.

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate in Data Analytics: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

Bachelors of Science in Biomedical Engineering: Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA

A 4-year Engineering degree with a multidisciplinary spread covering Electrical, Mechanical, and Biological concepts with an emphasis on end-user focused design skills.